<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Islamic Application</string>

    <string-array name="wude_english">
    <item>Step:1- Make niyyah (Intention) to perform Wudu. Niyyah is the Islamic concept of
        performing an act for the sake of Allah.</item>
        <item>Step:2- Wash your hands. Use your left hand to wash your right hand. Do this three
        times. After that, use your right hand to wash your left hand three times.</item>
        <item>Step:3- Take water into your mouth. Use your right hand to cup water into your
        mouth three times. Swish it around in your cheeks and the back of your throat.</item>
        <item>Step:4- Inhale water into your nose. Use your right hand to cup water and inhale
        it into your nose three times. You can use your left hand to close one nostril and blow out
        if you need to.</item>
        <item>Step:5- Wash your face. Wash your face three times by spreading your hands from
        your right ear to the left, and from the edge of the hair to the chin.</item>
        <item>Step:6- Wash your lower arms from wrists to elbows, leaving no part dry. From your
        wrist to your elbow, wash your right arm with your left hand three times and then wash your
        left arm with your right hand three times.</item>
        <item>Step:7- Clean your head. Using your wet hands, gently wipe your forehead from the
        eyebrow to the hairline. Also wipe down your hair, the back of your neck, and your temples.
        Do this one time.</item>
        <item>Step:8- Wipe your ears inside and out. With the same water, use your finger to
        clean all the crevices of your ear. Use your thumb to clean behind your ears from the bottom
        upward. This is also done one time.</item>
        <item>Step:9- Wash each of your feet. Clean up to the ankles and be sure water goes
        between the toes. Use your pinky finger and go through each toe to eliminate anything
        between. Start with your right foot and scrub each foot three times.</item>

    </string-array>
    <string-array name="wudu_urdu">
        // Urdu strings for translated version
        <item>اول: سب سے پہلے وضو کی نیت کریں۔ نیت اللہ سے رجوع کرنے کاایک اسلامی تصور ہے۔</item>
        <item>دوم: دونوں ہاتھ دھوئیں۔ بائیں ہاتھ سے دایاں ہاتھ دوئیں۔
یہ عمل تین بار دہرائیں۔ اس کے بعد دائیں ہاتھ سے بایاں ہاتھ دھوئیں۔         </item>

        <item>سوم: منہ میں پانی ڈالیں۔پانی دائیں ہاتھ سے ڈالیں۔
یہ عمل تین بار دہرائیں۔ پانی حلق تک جانا چاہیے۔         </item>
        <item>چہارم: ناک میں پانی ڈالیں۔
ناک میں پانی دائیں ہاتھ سے ڈالیں۔ بائیں ہاتھ سے ناک صاف کریں۔ یہ عمل تین بار دہرائیں۔          </item>
        <item>پنجم: منہ دھوئیں۔منہ دھوتے وقت اس بات کا خیال رکھیں کہ
پانی ایک کان سے دوسرے کان تک اور پیشانی سے ٹھوڑی تک جانا چاہیے۔         </item>
        <item>ششم: دونوں بازووُں کو کلائی سے کہنی تک دھوئیں اور کوئی حصہ خشک نہ رہنے دیں۔ دائیں
ہاتھ سے بایاں اور بائیں ہاتھ سے دایاں ہاتھ دھوئیں۔ یہ عمل تین بار دہرائیں۔          </item>
        <item>سر پر گیلے ہاتھ پھیر کر صاف کریں۔
ہاتھوں کو پہلے کنپٹیوں تک لے کر آئیں پھر گردن پر لے جائیں۔         </item>
        <item>ہشتم: کانوں میں انگلی ڈال کر صاف کریں۔
کانوں کے اندر اور باہر اچھی طرح انگلی پھیریں۔ انگوٹھے سے کان کی لو کو صاف کریں۔         </item>
        <item>نہم: دونوں پاوُں دھوئیں۔ ٹخنے سے پاوُں کے انگوٹھے اور ایڑھی تک پانی ڈالیں۔
پاوُں کی انگلیاں اچھی طرح دھوئیں تا کہ دھول مٹی وغیرہ صاف ہو جائے۔          </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="nimaz_eng">
<item>1: Prepare for Salah. Preparing for prayer includes cleaning yourself, wearing clean
            clothes, and finding a clean and pure place to pray.</item>
        <item>2: Stand to face the Qibla. The Qibla is the direction towards the Kaaba. Some
            compasses modified for this purpose are now available. Many hotel rooms also have the
            Qibla direction marked somewhere on the roof.</item>
        <item>3: Make the intention to pray. You do not need to say it out loud, but you will need to
            know which prayer of the day you are performing, what will be the type of the rakaat,
            and the number of rakaats.</item>
        <item>4: Perform the Takbiratul Ihram. This starts the prayer. Raise your hands, palms facing
            forwards, up till your ear lobes (or to your shoulders if you are a woman). Say out
            loud \"Allahu Akbar\"</item>
        <item>5: Perform Qiyam. Qiyam is where you stand up, your hands folded across your chest.
            Begin reciting Surah Al Fatiha (the first chapter in the order of the Quran) and
            another portion (Surah) of the Qur\'an.</item>
        <item>6: Perform the Ruk\'u. The ruku is basically a bow. You unfold your hands and bow,
            then placing your hands on your knees.Your back should become parallel to the ground,
            almost like carrying a glass of water on your back.</item>
        <item>7: Rise up. Rise up from the bow, while saying, \"Sam\'i Allahu liman hamidah
                (سمع الله لمن حمده) which means Allah listens to those who praise Him. Then say, Rabana
            walakel hummed (ربنا لك الحمد)              </item>
        <item>8: Perform the prostration. Say Allahu Akbar (الله أَكْبَر) once again and prostrate on the
            ground. Make sure you have placed your forehead, palms, and knees all on the floor,
            touching the ground.</item>
        <item>9: Rise to a sitting position, saying Allahu Akbar (الله أَكْبَر). When you are in this
            position, you must keep your eyes staring at your lap. Men must turn up the heel,
            and bend the toes, of the right foot. Women must keep both their feet and soles up
            under their body.</item>
        <item>10: Prostrate again, saying Allahu Akbar (الله أَكْبَر). The second prostration is exactly
            identical to the first one.</item>
        <item>11: Rise up to proceed to the next raka\'at, saying Allahu Akbar (الله أَكْبَر). The second
            raka\'at is identical to the first one up till the second prostration, but without the
            Takbiratul Ihram.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="nimaz_ur">
<item>۔ نماز کی تیاری: نماز کی ادائیگی کے لیے ضروری ہے
            کہ آپ کا جسم، کپڑے، اور نماز پڑھنے کی جگہ پاک اور صاف ہو۔ اس کے بعد وضو کریں۔</item>
        <item>۔ قبلہ رخ کھڑے ہو جائیں اور
            اپنی نظریں سجدے کی جگہ پر مرکوز رکھیں اور آپ کے پاوُں کے درمیان جگہ برابر ہونی چاہیے۔</item>
        <item>نماز کی نیت کریں۔ اللہ اکبر کہیں اور اپنے ہاتھوں کو کانوں تک اٹھائیں۔</item>
        <item>تکبیرۃ‘ الاحرام کہیں۔ نماز کا آغاز ہو چکا ہے۔ اب اپنے ہاتھ
            پیٹ پراس طرح باندھ لیں کہ ایک ہتھیلی دوسری کے اوپر آئے۔ اب باآوازِ بلند اللہ اکبر کہیں۔</item>
        <item>قیام میں کھڑے ہو جائیں اور سورۃ فاتحہ کی تلاوت کریں۔ اس کے بعد کوئی اور سورۃ تلاوت کریں۔</item>
        <item>رکوع کریں۔ اللہ اکبر کہیں اور اپنے ہاتھ کھول کر گھٹنوں پر رکھ لیں۔ آپکی کمرزمین کے بالکل متوازی ہونی چاہیے۔
            کمر کے اوپر یا نیچے ہونے سے رکوع نہیں ہوگا۔ تین بار سبحانَ ربی العظیم کہیں۔</item>
        <item>رکوع سے سیدھا ہونے کے بعد باآوازِ بلند لمع اللہ لمن حمدہ کہیں۔ پھر کہیں ربنا لک الحمدہ۔</item>
        <item>اللہ اکبر کہیں اور سجدہ کریں۔ اس بات کا خیال رکھیں کہ آپ کی پیشانی، ہتھیلیاں، گھٹنے اور پاوُں زمین کے
            ساتھ لگے ہوں اور کہنیاں زمین سے اٹھی ہوں۔ سجدے کے دوران سبحان ربی الاعلیٰ تین بار کہیں۔</item>
        <item>اللہ اکبر کہتے ہوئے تشہد میں بیٹھ جائیں۔ اس حالت میں اپنی آنکھیں گود پر مرکوز رکھیں۔</item>

        <item>اللہ اکبر کہتے ہوئے دوبارہ سجدہ کریں۔ سجدے کا طریقہ وہی ہے جو پہلے بیان کیا گیا ہے۔</item>
        <item>اللہ اکبر کہہ کر اگلی رکعت شروع کریں۔ دوسری رکعت کا طریقہ بھی پہلی کی طرح ہی ہے۔</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hajj_english">
<item>Step:1- Preparing for the Hajj. Be ready to reach at mina by 8th of Dhu al-Hijjah night.
            Shave, comb your hair, trim or shape your facial hair, cut your nails, and remove unwanted body hair.
            Bathe (or perform wudu, partial ablution) with the intention of Ihram.</item>
        <item>Step:2- intention to perform Hajj.for men Ihram sheets wrap one around your waist
            and wear the other over and do Niyyah: \"O Allah! I intend to perform Hajj.
            Please make it easy for me and accept it from me. Amen</item>
        <item>Step:3- Head to Mina. After the sunrise travel towards mina and so
            spend your time praying and in tasbih,in mina perform Dhuhr, Asr, Magrib,Isha and
            9th Dhu al-Hijjah prayers and stay there.</item>
        <item>Step:4- Head to Arafat. On the second day of Hajj, pilgrims travel to Arafat,
            Pilgrims must reach Arafat by the afternoon because, at this time, a ritual called Waquf begins.</item>
        <item>Step:5- Pray in Muzdalifah. After sundown, pilgrims head to a place called Muzdalifah between Mina
            and Arafat. Here, they offer an evening prayer to God (Maghrib) and spend the night sleeping on
            the ground</item>
        <item>Step:6- Perform Ramy in Mina. Before the sun rises, pilgrims head back to Mina. Here,
            pilgrims participate in a ceremony meant to symbolize stoning the devil. Pilgrims throw
            seven consecutive pebbles at a special stone monument called the Jamrat al Aqabah.</item>
        <item>Step:7- Offer a sacrifice. After the Ramy ceremony, it\'s necessary to offer an animal
            sacrifice (Qurbani) to God</item>
        <item>Step:8- Get your hair cut or shaved. Men may have their hair completely shaved or cut into a
            very short haircut,Women can have a short lock of hair cut - their heads are not shaved.</item>
        <item>Step:9- Perform the Tawaf and Sa\'ey. the Hajj requires pilgrims to perform the Tawaf and
            Sa\'ey rituals at the Ka\'bah and the nearby hills.</item>
        <item>Step:10- Repeat Ramy after sundown on the fourth and fifth days. In Mina, you must once
            again participate in the stoning ritual. This time, you will not throw pebbles only at the Jamrat
            al Aqabah.</item>
        <item>Step:11- Perform the Farewell Tawaf. Finally, your Hajj has come to a close by walking
            around the Ka\'bah seven times as before</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hajj_urdu">
<item>اول: حج کی تیاری-  آٹھ ذی الحجہ کی رات کومنٰی جانے کی تیاری مکمل کرلیں-
    سر کے با ل سنواریں،خط بنوایں، ناخن کاٹیں،
    جسم کےغیرضروری بالوں کو صاف کریں- احرام کی نیت سے غسل کریں ورنہ وضو کر یں.</item>
        <item>دوم: حج کی نیت-  مرد ایک سفیذ چا د ر با ند ھیں اور دوسری اوڑھیں
    اور د ل میں نیت کریں کہ اے اللہ میں حج کر نا
    چا ہتا ھوں میرے لیے اِس کو آسان بنا دے اورقبول کر آمین-</item>
        <item>سوم: منیٰ کو روانگی-  طلوح آفتاب کے بعد منیٰ روانہ ھوں اور راستہ بھر زیادہ سے زیادہ تَلبِیَہ پڑھیں
    اور دیگر تسبیحات پڑھتے ر ھیں- منٰی میں ظہر، عصر، مغرب، عشاء
    اور 9 ذوالحجہ کی فجر کی نماز ادا کریں اور رات منیٰ میں رھیں۔</item>
        <item>چہارم: عرفات کوروانگی- حج کے دوسرے دن عرفات کی طرف جائیں۔
    حا جیوں کو دوپہرتک ضرورعرفات پہنچنا ھوتا ھے تا کے وقوف ادا کریں ۔</item>
        <item>پنجم: مُزدَلِفَہ میں عبادت کرنا- جب سورج ڈوب جاۓ توحاجیوں کومُزدَلِفَہ روانہ ہوجانا چاہیے جو منیٰ اور عرفات کے درمیان ھے-
            یہاں وہ شام اور رات کی نماز پڑتے ھیں اوروہاں ہی رات گزارتے ھیں-</item>
        <item> ششم: منٰی میں شیطان کو پتھر مارنا-
    سورج نکلنے سے پہلے حاجیوں کو منیٰ جانا ھوتا ھے یہاں ایک رسم ادا کی جاتی ھےجس میں سارے
    حاجیوں کو شیطان کو پتھر مارنے ھوتے ھیں-پھرجمرتہ العقبہ پر پہنچ کرسات لگاتار پتھر ماریں</item>
        <item>ہفتم: قربانی کرنا- رمی کے بعد ہرحاجی کے لیےضروری ھے کےوہ الگ الگ قربانی کرے</item>
        <item>ہشتم:  سرکےبال منڈواۓ-  مردوں کیلے لازمی ھے کے سارے بال منڈوائیں یا
    بلکل چھوٹے چھوٹے رہنے دیں عورتوں کےسارے نہی تھورےتھورے کاٹے جاتے ھیں-</item>
        <item>نہم: طواف اور سعی کریں-
    اسکے بعد حاجی کو چاہیے کے کعبہ اور نزدیک جو پہاڑی ھے اسکا طواف اور سعی کریں-</item>
        <item>دہم: پھر رمی کریں-
    چھوتھے اور پانچویں دن سورج غروب ھونے کے بعد پھر پتھر پیھنکنے والی رسم میں حصہ لیں،
    اس دفعہ آپ نے صرف جمرتہ العقبہ پر پتھر نہی پھینکتے بلکہ دوسرے پہاڑوں پر بھی</item>
        <item>یازدہم: آخری طواف ادا کریں-
    پھر آخری طواف کرکریں سا ت دفعہ کعبہ کا چکر لگا کرجیسے کے پہلے کیا تھا-</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>

</resources>





